https://fabercastellusa.myshopify.com/pages/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Faber-Castell USA, Inc. (“Faber-Castell,” “we” or “us”) respects your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.
This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the websites located at www.fabercastell.com, www.fabercastell.webdamdb.com, www.creativitycan.com, www.creativity-connection.com, www.creativityforkids.com, www.designmemorycraft.typepad.com and www.graf-von-faber-castell.us and all affiliated websites (our “Websites”) and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information.
We have designed our Websites with parents and children in mind.  We appreciate and respect our visitors' concerns for their safety when personal information is shared with us.  We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of all personal information that is submitted to us.  We do not sell or share any information to third parties.  While we take reasonable measures to safeguard the confidential information that you provide, Faber-Castell has no liability for the disclosure of any information that is obtained due to transmission errors or for the disclosure of any information obtained by any unauthorized acts by third parties.
This policy applies to information we collect:
On our Websites;
In e-mail, text and other electronic messages between you and our Websites; or
Through mobile and desktop applications you download from our Websites, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and our Websites.
It does not apply to information collected by:
Us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by Company or any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries); or
Any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries).
Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Websites. By accessing or using our Websites, you agree and consent to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time (see the section below entitled Changes to our Privacy Policy). Any changes or updates to the privacy policy are effective immediately upon posting to the Websites and your continued use of the Websites after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.
If you wish to browse the Websites, you may generally do so anonymously.  There is no need to provide any personal information while browsing our Websites.  If you choose to contact us requesting assistance with products, product information or general questions we ask for your personal information on our contact us page. This information helps us process your inquiry and provide the best service possible.
Children Under the Age of 13We adhere to the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) on our Websites as well as offline.  A child’s privacy is important to us.  No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on our Websites. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the Websites or on or through any of the features on the Websites, make any purchases through the Websites, or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or any screen name or user name you may use.  If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.  Providing any personal information regarding a child, including the child’s name and age is strictly at the parent’s discretion.  At any time a parent can request to review their personal information and their child's personal information that they have submitted to us.  A parent may also ask to have it deleted by sending a request to consumer@fabercastell.com.  If a visitor to the Websites is under the age of 18, they should read the privacy policy with their parents for guidance.
Information We Collect About You and How We Collect ItWe collect several types of information from and about users of our Websites, including information:
By which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, or any other information the Websites collect that is defined as personal or personally identifiable information under an applicable law (“personal information”);
That is about you but individually does not identify you, such as your such as your demographic, gender, location; and/or
About your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Websites and usage details.
We collect this information:
Directly from you when you provide it to us; and/or
Automatically as you navigate through the site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses and information collected through cookies, web beacons and other tracking technologies.
Information You Provide to UsThe information we collect on or through our Websites may include:
Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Websites, which includes, but is not limited to, information provided at the time of subscribing to our service, or requesting further services (e.g., First Name, Last Name, Address, Phone Number);
Information collected when you report a problem with our Websites;
Records and copies of your correspondence (including e-mail addresses), if you contact us; and/or
Details of transactions you carry out through our Websites and of the fulfillment of your orders (you may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our Websites).
Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection TechnologiesAs you navigate through and interact with our Website, we (or a third party designated by us) may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns, including:
Details of your visits to our Websites, including traffic data, location data, logs and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Websites.
Information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, the page(s) you request, the domain name of the website from which you may link to the Website, your computer operating system and browser type.
The information we (or a third party designated by us) collect automatically is statistical data and does not include personal information. It helps us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to:
Estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Websites according to your individual interests.
Speed up your searches.
Recognize you when you return to our Websites.
The technologies we (or a third party designated by us) use for this automatic data collection may include:
Cookies (or browser cookies) - A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. Generally, we use cookies to remind us of who you are, tailor our products and services to suit your personal interests, estimate our audience size, assist our online merchants to track visits to and sales at our sites and to process your order, track your status in our promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and/or analyze your visiting patterns.  You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Websites. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Websites.
Flash Cookies - Certain features of our Websites may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Websites. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. For information about managing your privacy and security settings for Flash cookies, see the section entitled Choices about How We Use and Disclose Your Information below.
Web Beacons - Pages of our the Websites and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit Faber-Castell, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).
How We Use Your InformationWe may use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:
When you submit your personal information to us unless you specify otherwise, you are entered into our consumer database.  You are then on our list to receive e-mails regarding our special promotional offers and new product introductions periodically.  We will not send you junk mailings or mail that contains pop ups, only information about our products and specials that are being offered;
To present our Websites and its contents to you;
To provide you with information that you request from us;
To fulfill orders for products or services that you may place through the Websites or for any other purpose for which you provide it;
To provide you with notices about your account;
To notify you about changes to our Websites or any products or services we offer or provide though it;
In any other way we may describe when you provide the information; or
For any other purpose with your consent.
We may also use your information to contact you about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please indicate as such on the order form. For more information, see the section titled Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information below.
Online OrderingWhen you place an online order the following information is required to process and fulfill your order, send order confirmation and tracking information to you.  customer’s name, billing address, shipping address, e-mail address and credit card information.  Customers must be 18 years of age or older and must use a valid credit card to purchase products online.  In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we will not knowingly collect personal information from or provide our services to persons under the age of 18. All internet purchasing transactions are performed on Shopatron, a secure site operated by an un-affiliated third party company, Shopatron Inc.  To view the Shopatron privacy policy please visit: http://ecommerce.shopatron.com/privacy-policy.
Disclosure of Your InformationWe may disclose aggregated information about our users without restriction.
We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy:
To our subsidiaries and affiliates;
To contractors, service providers and other third parties we use to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them;
To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of Faber-Castell USA, Inc.’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by Faber-Castell USA, Inc. about our Website users is among the assets transferred;
To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it;
For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information; or
With your consent.
We may also disclose your personal information:
To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request;
To enforce or apply our terms of use (located at www.fabercastell.com/company/terms-of-use) and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes; or
If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Faber-Castell USA, Inc., our customers or others.
Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your InformationWe strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:
Tracking Technologies and Advertising - You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe’s website. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
Communications from Faber-Castell - If you wish to opt-out of receiving any future communication from us, including e-mail offers and updates, and would like to be removed from our database, please send your request to webmaster@fabercastell.com.  Please include the e-mail address that you originally sent to us.  This opt out does not apply to information provided to Faber-Castell as a result of a product purchase, product service experience or other transactions.
Text Marketing and NotificationsBy subscribing to text notifications you agree to receive recurring automated marketing text messages at the phone number provided. Consent is not a condition of purchase. Text STOP to unsubscribe or HELP for help. Msg and data rates may apply. View Terms of use and privacy policy.
Data SecurityFaber-Castell must collect certain information in order to operate the Websites and to fulfill your requests or enable participation in certain online activities. We have implemented reasonable security measure designed to secure the personal information under our control from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. We use industry-standard practices, such as encrypted storage and password protection systems, to safeguard the confidentiality of information. The third party Shopatron online shopping service used by the Websites has built-in security measures to protect your information from loss, misuse and alteration.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Websites. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Websites.
Changes to Our Privacy PolicyThis policy may change from time to time. It is our practice to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. Any changes or updates to the privacy policy are effective immediately upon posting to the Websites and your continued use of the Websites after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the bottom of this page. You are responsible for periodically visiting our Websites and this privacy policy to check for any changes.
Contact InformationTo ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at:  consumer@fabercastell.com.
Last modified: [11/13/2020]
